Nikolaos Liliakidis

Brighton, East Sussex, BN2 9YF

Mobile: 07575855085 Email: nickliliakides@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://nickliliakides.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nick-liliakides-820a7236/
GitHub:https://github.com/nickliliakides

Personal Profile

I'm an ambitious, flexible and hardworking person, really passionate and focused on full-stack Web development, comfortable on building RESTful APIs from scratch using MERN stack and with great attention to detail. I have been interested in programming and computing since I was nine years old and this led me to complete an IT Degree in my home country, Just IT self-funded professional web developer course and my passion for learning new languages and technologies stays imperishable, continuing to gain educational experiences in completion of IT degree at the UK's Open University.

I'm seeking to undertake web and software development tasks and challenges, full responsibly, for personal and career development. My first priority and challenge is to see myself as a senior full-stack developer as soon as possible gaining through my employment new skills and knowledge to progress further my career within a challenging environment.

Education and IT Training

07/2017- 01/2018 Just IT Training Ltd, London Development Professional Programme

- MTA Software Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MTA HTML5 Web Application Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Application (Expected 2017)

08/2014-06/2020 The Open University, UK

Bachelor Degree - BSc (Honours) Computing and IT, Part Time

Core Modules: Sense Programming, Robotics (Robotlab programming simulator)

Microsoft Networking, Linux, Maths, Web Technologies

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Python. SQL

08/2011-08/2012 BHMS, Business and Hotel Management School Lucerne Switzerland

Post Graduate Diploma in Hospitality and Business Management

09/2001-06/2003 National Institute of Professional Training and Education Thessaloniki, Greece

Certified Degree in "Applications Technician on ITs and Networks"

Core Modules: MS Office (Word, Excel, Access), Pascal, Visual-Basic, C++, Unix, SQL,

Networking Essentials, Maths, Computer Hardware Essentials

IT Skills

Development Core Skills: JavaScript-TypeScript, React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, SQL

Web Technologies and Frameworks: HTML5, CSS-SASS, ASP.Net, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Semantic UI

Core Programming Languages: JavaScript-TypeScript, C#, Python, Java

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, Linux, Android

Projects:

My best projects are presented on my portfolio website

"https://nickliliakides.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/" in Projects section where the visitors can see all details, demonstration and links to read the code in Github.

Employment History

10/2020-present

Sportbuff, London, UK

https://sportbuff.com/

Frontend engineer (pemanent)

- Building company's dashboards(Content, Admin and Metrics).
- Technologies: React, Redux(Thunk-Sagas), Typescript.
- Testing: Jest, Enzyme for unit tests Cypress for integration tests

10/2019-08/2020

WinMan ERP Software, Brighton, UK

http://www.winman.com/

Frontend developer (permanent)

- Building and improving the UI of company's main ERP software cloud application.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS-Sass, Javascript(React-Redux-Vanilla-JQuery), C#, Razor pages.
- Frameworks: ASP.Net Core, Bootstrap, SyncFusion, Datatables.js, Chart.js
- Source control using Git, Visual Studio integated Git tool plus command line.

12/2018-08/2019

R3ality Projects, Brighton, UK

http://www.realityprojects.co.uk

Frontend developer (contract)

- Developing a gas company client management application.
- Core libraries and frameworks used: React, Redux, MaterialUI, Jest and Enzyme.
- Basic React template Fuse2 and source control via git and sourcetree.
- Other libraries used: axios, moxios, lodash, react-dropzone, react-table etc.

08/2017-Present

Hermes Web Development(HWD My LTD), London - Brighton, UK

https://hermeswebdev.co.uk

Founder/Director/Full-stack Developer

- Creating e-commerce solutions and web applications using MERN stack. (HTML, CSS-SaSS, JavaScript, React-Redux, Node-Express, MongoDB-Mongoose).
- Seeking and finding suitable domain, database and hosting services for our clients.
- Supporting, upgrading and maintaining our creations.

03/2018-04/2018

Farmco International, Watford, UK Web Developer (8 weeks placement)

- ASP.Net Core Unit Testing.
- Testing and debugging code of Company's leading upcoming projects.

02/2013-10/2016

E-Business Solutions, Thessaloniki, Greece Web Developer(Remote)

- Supporting new businesses to be established.
- Web design and development(Mainly used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MicrosoftSQL).
- Digital Marketing.
- Consulting and technical support.

10/2012-07/2017

The Real Greek, Spitalfields Market, London, UK Restaurant Supervisor/Assistant Manager

- Dealing with stock, orders and invoices, inputting data into the company's database system.
- Organizing and cooperating with front and back of the house to run busy shifts smoothly.
- Dealing with 'difficult' customers and complaints and solving problems that occur.
- Banking and closing daily shifts, reporting and sending numbers and stats to the head office and operations.

06/2010-08/2011

Junknet Internet Station, Kalamaria, Thessaloniki, Greece Front Office Administrator, Assistant Manager

- Logging clients into the network and managing the server application.
- Front desk management duties.
- Fixing technical problems and issues on software and hardware devices.

02/2004-09/2010

Digital DVD movies, videogames, Internet Cafe and IT services Thessaloniki, Greece

Owner, Director, General Manager

- Selling and renting movies, videogames and data media.
- Providing a Local Area Network for customers and groups to surf the web and play onine games.
- Providing technical support on software and hardware of computers and mobile devices.
- Developing company's website.

Interests and Achievements

Computing: Since I was 9 years old I was writing programs on Basic and playing games on my AMSTRAD CPC 6128 or my friend's Spectrum, Commodore 64 and a bit later Atari ST and Amiga game consoles back to 80s and 90s. Since early on 21th century I use Internet and computers in a more advanced level and I also studied and became software, hardware and network technician. I use very efficient plenty of Operating systems, application and services like: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Ableton, Sound Forge, Social Media, Remote connection services and many more. Except technologies and Web I have a big passion for music(mixing and production), cinema, sports and quality food.

References available upon request